

Opeyemi Dada

Backend/ Embedded System Engineer

A solution driven and hardworking graduate of the federal polytechnic Ilaro with proven technical research and communication skills. I was once research intern at the federal polytechnic ilaro where i decided to hone my software development skill along side my hardware skills.

✓ dadaadeife@gmail.com	⋙ http://https://twitter.com/adeinfo365
🗣 39 iyabode akinola street eledi estate ota, Ado Odo, Nigeria	https://github.com/adeife16
[] 08118671802	含 https://stackoverflow.com/users/11216949/ade-coder
© 08151298486	in https://linkedin.com/in/opeyemi-dada-b52b46155
f https://facebook.com/adeife95	Q http://quora.com/profile/Adeife-Dada

EDUCATION

Higher National Diploma

The Federal Polytechnic Ilaro

10/2019 - 10/2021

Computer Engineering

Ordinary National Diploma

The Federal Polytechnic Ilaro

10/2016 - 10/2018

Computer Engineering

Secondary School Certificate Examination

Renics College Lagos

07/2009 - 07/2012

Computer Engineering

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Intern

The Federal Polytechnic Ilaro

03/2021 - 11/2021

Department of Computer Engineering

Tasks and Achievements

- Setting up of both hardware and software development environment for the research work.
- Simulation of several digital communication modulation schemes using a software defined radion (SDR).
- Generation and collection of pictorial modulation in form of constellation images using python script.
- Preprocessing and filtering collected dataset for machine learning algorithm development.
- Configuration of physical telecommunication radio for field work.

Contact: Engr. J. Olasina (M.sc) - 08037243084

Full-stack Web Developer (Freelance) JAAD Logistics

06/2021 - 03/2022

Jaad Logistics Services Lagos

Tasks and Achievements

- Design and implementation of SQL database required for the website to run.
- Design and implementation of the front-end and user interface of the website using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Javscript.
- · Implementation of third party APIs.
- Development of APIs to connect front-end with Back-end.
- Development of backend logic using PHP language.
- Version control using github.

Contact: Mr Joseph - 07062869423

Database Developer (Freelance)

04/2022 - 04/2022

Tasks and Achievements

- Environmental setup for database implementation
- Database structure definition using oracle SQLplus.
- · Data population using oracle SQLplus.
- Connection of database to oracle forms using oracle forms developer software.

Contact: Mr Gabriel Olusoji - 08038252652

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- HTML proficiency 99%
- CSS proficiency 70%;
- Javascript proficiency 90%
- PHP proficiency 90%
- Python proficiency 80%
- NodeJs proficiency 60%
- SQL proficiency 80%
- NoSQL(MongoDB) proficiency 70%
- C++ proficiency 60%
- Arduino proficiency 70%
- Linux proficiency 70%
- Git proficiency 50%
- Electronics Circuit Design proficiency 60%
- Networking proficiency 40%
- Machine Learning proficiency 50%

Soft Skills

- Verbal and written communication
- Time Management
- Flexibility
- Teamwork
- Optimism

INTERESTS

Artificial Intelligence

Internet of Things (IOT)

Robotics

Embedded System

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Horace (08/2021 - Present)

 A web based school management systems meant to reduce the work load of teachers, make learning more fun for students and ease parent in monitoring the academic performance of their children.

Sign Language Translator (03/2022 - Present

 An artificial intelligence based system the helps interprete the american sign language thereby aiding communication for visually impaired and vocally impaired people.

LANGUAGES

English - Native Proficiency

Yoruba - Native Proficiency